SHUBHAM UPADHYAY

Bengaluru, Karnataka

Languages Spoken: English & Hindi

Summary

A data-driven guy whose goal is to turn data into information and information into insight. I primarily take interest in Developer Advocacy, Product Management, and Community Management. I have been into communities for the last 4 years and have a fair amount of experience in building and running developer programs.

Work History

Skillenza [Program Manager] December 2019 - Present

- At Skillenza, we help organizations to build a community by running engaging programs and targeting the right set of Professional Developers. Every organization has specific ROIs, some lookout for hiring top-notch developers, some concentrate on pushing their content or product through these programs and some do it for branding.
- My role as a Program Manager is to help our clients strategize, market and execute the Program [end-to-end] while building communities on our platform. Apart from this, I have organized multiple meetups for Skillenza across India in different cities for Developers and was also responsible for evangelizing Skillenza Platform.

[Intern - Developer Relations] August 2019 - November 2019

I was involved in building a community called Devengers which is sponsored by Microsoft. We scaled the community to 9000+ developers in 7 months and organized engaging hackathons and events for the community members. Since I was building communities, during this time I got the opportunity to get connected with Industrial Experts and also ensured we market our events or activities in the best possible way. Mobile: +91 9555726005

Email: shubham.upadhyay97@gmail.com

Professional Links

Website - <u>shubhamspeaks.com</u>

Medium - medium.com/@iamshubhamupadhyay

LinkedIn - <u>linkedin.com/in/iamshubhamu</u> Twitter - twitter.com/iamshubamu

GitHub - github.com/iamshubhamupadhyay

Skills

- Program Management
- Developer Advocacy
- Community Management
- Product Management
- Content Writing
- Social Champ (Twitter/Blogs)

Tools & Technologies

- Microsoft Excel
- Canva
- Google Analytics

Education

- B.Tech [2016 20202] in Computer Science & Engineering from SRM University, Chennai with 81%.
- XII th Standard [2015 2016]
 Completed my 12th in the year 2016
 from LBS under CBSE with 70%
 aggregate.
- X th Standard[2013 2014] Completed 10th in 2014 from Birla Public School, Pilani under CBSE with 82 % aggregate.

SPACENOS [Product Management Intern]

May 2018 - August 2018

 Worked on a learning management system named Educate in strategizing Sales for B2C module, product implementation, market research, and project planning

Community Initiatives & Experience

DevRel Community [Co-Founder]January 2019 - Present

 DevRel Community is an initiative for building a community of Developer Relations in India. It's an open community of Developers Ecosystem focussing on DevRel. Our Community has expanded in India and Singapore.

HACKFERENCE [Co-Founder & COO]

July 2018 - Present

 Hackference India is an Open Community mounted towards the goal of reaching India's biggest Open Source Community event which comprises DevRel Conf, adding to that there's hiring opportunity to inform of Hackathon and Hiring Fair. The first edition was hosted in Bangalore, IN. [www.hackference.in]

Mozilla Foundation [Volunteer] September 2017 - Present

Engage the community by establishing Mozilla Clubs with the goal
of spreading Web Literacy. Involve youth participation in Web
Literacy Campaigns to demystify the web. Successfully Led
#IHRinINDIA Internet Health Report Campaign in New Delhi, India2018. Contributor to the Dark Funnel Campaign.

Google Developers Group - Chennai Circle [Volunteer] October 2018 - Present

 Volunteering for GDG events in and around Chennai. Organised GDG DEVFEST 2018 Chennai.

Growth Folks - Chennai Chapter [Chennai Lead] February 2019 - December 2020

 Growth Folks is a community/group of Growth Hackers, Marketers, Digital Marketers, and Marketing Enthusiast having a simple yet common mindset: To Grow. Built a community chapter in Chennai.

Accomplishments

- Blockchain Over Transaction System [2018] Published in IEEE
- Big Data Analysis on Supply Chain Management [2018] Published in - IEEE

Non-Academic Responsibilities

CHIPSET

[President / Club Member]

CHIPSET is an initiative to engage students from Dept. of CSE, SRM University, Ramapuram, that provides an open forum for discussion on various technologies and topics based on both technical and non-technical aspects of our profession.

TEXUS SRM RAMAPURAM [VICE PRESIDENT]

A National Level Techfest which included 50+ Technical & Non-Technical Events, Hackathon and many more. This event engaged 5000+ students from over 10+ National Level esteemed colleges/universities across Tamilnadu.